infoq.com 2019-12-25

# InfoQ - Facilitating the spread of knowledge and innovation in enterprise software development

## Who we are

C4 Media, Inc is a global publisher (InfoQ.com) and events company (QCon). We strive to deliver services to our clients and partners using data protection and privacy by design practices. We promote responsible and purpose-driven data collection and use. We adhere and comply with the relevant data protection law globally. We provide transparent and accountable data protection process in all that we do.

## What this notice covers

This privacy notice tells you what to expect when InfoQ.com collects, uses and shares personal information. It explains how we use your personal data and your rights in relation to that data. This privacy notice covers InfoQ.com, operated by C4 Media, Inc.

## Information InfoQ Collects

InfoQ collects information about you from a variety of sources, including:

  * Information we collect from you directly
  * Information we collect about you when you call us, visit our sites, use our mobile applications or services, or view our online advertisements
  * Information we collect about you from other sources, such as social media, public and commercially available sources
  * Information shared with us by our business partners

All the information InfoQ collects about you may be combined to improve our communications with you and to develop world-class services.

## Use of cookies by InfoQ

You can read more about how we use cookies on our cookie page.

## Links to third party sites and social media

InfoQ sites may include links to third party sites. InfoQ does not control these third-party sites, and we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every site you visit.

InfoQ uses “plugins” (such as the Facebook “Like” button) to third-party sites or offer login (such as login with Facebook, Linkedin and Twitter) through a third-party account. Third-party plugins and login features, including their loading, operation and use, are governed by the privacy policy and terms of the third-party providing them.

## Uses & Information Sharing our Choices

InfoQ uses the information we collect for InfoQ business purposes such as:

  * To provide the services you request
  * To tell you about InfoQ services and those offered by our carefully selected business partners
  * To manage our sites and services
  * We may sell or rent your personal information to sponsors, clients or third party agencies only on an appropriate legal basis such as legitimate interest or consent
  * We keep your data within the European Union (EU) or countries with EU adequacy status

We may share your information:

  * With our business clients for the provision of professional services such as data privacy consultancy, but only if the business client or we have obtained your consent; With our third-party service providers who perform InfoQ business operations on our behalf
  * As part of a sale of a InfoQ brand to another company
  * To protect and defend InfoQ (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions)
  * When required by law and/or government authorities
  * You have the right not to provide personal information to InfoQ, this may mean InfoQ are not be able to provide the services you request, or to tell you about other services offered by InfoQ.

## Your Choices

  * You can stop receiving promotional emails from InfoQ by following the instructions in those messages, or through this Privacy Notice.
  * You have the right to withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal data by InfoQ, where consent was the basis of the processing
  * You have the right to have your personal data erased (right to be forgotten), InfoQ will make every reasonable effort to remove any reference to your personal data if they have shared it with any 3rd party during their usual business processes.
  * In some instances you have the right to have your personal data transferred to another company and InfoQ will make every reasonable effort to comply with your request.
  * You have the right to raise any concerns to the processing or use of your personal data by InfoQ to an appropriate data protection authority.
  * You have the right to review personal data InfoQ holds on you if this does not impact on other individual’s rights and freedoms

## Important Information

InfoQ is committed to working with clients and data protection authorities to resolve any privacy concern.

InfoQ complies with EU data protection laws.

## Contact

You can contact InfoQ by writing to:

C4Media Inc. (InfoQ.com),  
2275 Lake Shore Boulevard West,  
Suite #325,  
Toronto, Ontario, Canada,  
M8V 3Y3  

Or emailing us at: [privacy@c4media.com](mailto:privacy@c4media.com)

## This Privacy Notice

This notice is reviewed by InfoQ on a regular basis and should be checked by individuals for the latest updates.

Last update: May, 2019

## Privacy notice scope

Trust is a cornerstone of our company ethos. InfoQ is committed to maintaining your trust by protecting personal information that we collect and use.

This fair processing notification describes the information that InfoQ collects about you; how we use and protect this information; the choices you can make about how we use this information; and how you can correct or update your information.

## Information InfoQ collects

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources. This includes information we collect directly from you; information we collect when you visit our sites, view our online content, visit our events and information we collect about you from other sources.

## Information we collect directly from you:

We collect information directly from you when you choose to participate in our offers and programs, create an account on our websites, call or email us, or otherwise provide information directly to us. The following are examples of information we may collect directly from you:

  * Name;
  * Email address;
  * Postal address;
  * Username and password;
  * Username and password;
  * Demographic information;
  * Payment information (such as a credit card & Bank details);
  * Future communication preferences;
  * Location;
  * Social media handles that you may share with us when you registering with InfoQ.

## Information we collect when you visit our sites, view our online ads or promotions, or other services

We use cookies and other technologies to collect information when you visit our sites, view our online advertisements or promotions, or other services. The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies:

  * Information about your device browser and operating system;
  * IP address;
  * Web pages you view;
  * Links you click;
  * InfoQ emails you open;
  * Bugs you report.

All the information we collect about you may be combined to help us improve our communications with you and to develop our services.

InfoQ is a data processor and keep written records of all data processing undertaking as required by EU privacy regulations.

## InfoQ Business Purposes

We use the information we collect to provide you offers and services, to deliver to you advertisements, send you email communications relating to our content, offers or other content tailored to your interests, and to conduct other InfoQ business operations.

The following are examples of how we may use the information we collect:

  * Answer your questions or respond to your requests;
  * Send IT related information you may be interested in buying or using as a service;
  * Develop new products and services;
  * Resolves bugs and improve user experience;
  * Create and manage your account;
  * Process payment for purchases or other services;
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions;
  * Send you an email and/or postal messages with information about InfoQ brands and other content we think may be of interest to you, including brand and service information from carefully selected business partners and sponsors;
  * Develop and provide advertising tailored to your interests, including interest-based advertising;
  * Personalise your experience on our websites by presenting services and information tailored to you;
  * Analyse the use of our services and advertising;
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our business.

The success of our business depends on your trust. We may share your personal information to sponsors, clients or third agencies only on an appropriate legal basis such as legitimate interest or consent. We share your personal information within InfoQ and as described in this Policy notice. We do not share personal information with marketers outside of InfoQ unless you consent to such sharing, or as described within this Privacy Notice.

## Co-Promotions with Carefully selected business partners

InfoQ may collect personal and other information for a co-promotion or joint program with a business partner, sponsors and share your information with that business partner. For these programs, we will make clear at the point of collection that the information will be shared with InfoQ and the participating business partner and ask for your consent as required by applicable laws. 

## Third-party service providers

For example, we may rely on a service provider to:

  * Fulfill your service requests and answer your questions;
  * Host our sites and deliver our email or other communications;
  * Manage payments or take other actions on our behalf;
  * Analyse our data, sometimes combined with data from other sources, to send you communications or provide professional services;
  * Conduct research and analyse data to improve our products, services and sites.
  * Where permitted by law, we may combine personal information about you that InfoQ has collected, with personal information about you that a business partner has collected, so we can jointly send tailored promotional communications to you or to complete professional services we have been instructed to undertake. In such instances, our business partner will not be permitted to use InfoQ data or the combined data for its own, independent marketing purposes. Our service provider will only be allowed to use the combined set of information to send you joint communications that we hope will be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive these joint communications, you can always opt out by following the instructions provided in any such communication or through this Privacy Policy as indicated above;
  * Perform other services that we request.

We rely on third-party service providers to perform a variety of business operations on our behalf. In so doing, we may need to share your personal information with them. We provide our service providers with only the personal information they need to perform the services we request, and we require that they protect this information and not use it for any other purpose.

## Other situations

We may disclose your personal information:

  * As part of the sale of a InfoQ brand to another company;
  * To protect and defend the rights and property of InfoQ (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions);
  * When required by law and/or government authorities;
  * To fulfill contracted professional services such as data privacy related consultancy.

## Personal information retention period

We will retain Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

Examples:

  * When you notify us, you wish to come off our mailing lists, we will erase your data within 4 weeks;
  * We may keep your personal data for periods as stipulated under our data classification policy, for example 10 years if the information relates to health and safety;
  * Client personal information is regularly updated and deleted if no longer necessary as outlined above but a least every 12 months.

## Aggregated and Non-personal information

We share aggregated and/or anonymous information that does not identify you for InfoQ business purposes. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to InfoQ sites or services. We may also share aggregated and/or anonymous information with our business partners for their own business purposes.

## Information Security

InfoQ is committed to keeping personal information secure. We have implemented technical, administrative and physical procedures designed to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information secure using appropriate technologies such as firewalls and password management.

## Information Transfer

InfoQ may transfer your personal information within InfoQ and/or to other third parties, such as our third-party service providers. Your personal information may be transferred to, stored and processed in a country other than the one in which it was collected. This information will remain within the European Union or countries with appropriate adequacy status.

We have implemented procedures and controls to help ensure that personal information is protected no matter what country it is stored in or transferred to.

## Children's Online Privacy

We do not intend to collect personal information online from children under the age of 13 or as defined by local legal requirements.

## Legal effects and impact to individuals

In some cases, the personal information you provide our clients (data controllers) may form contractual or legal obligation and may have a significant impact on the individual or individuals providing the information. For example, we are obliged to share information under legal warrant to a law enforcement agency. If you decide not to provide personal information, InfoQ may not be able to complete the data processing on behalf of our clients. The provision of personal information direct to InfoQ would not normally in itself adversely affect an individual.

## Your choices & access to your information

We give you choices about how we communicate with you.

## Email Communications

If you have given us your email for purposes of communication or promotion, we will use your data to contact you or send promotional emails relating to your interests. You may revoke your consent to being contacted by email for promotional purposes any time, by clicking on an unsubscribe link.

Further, with your consent, we may make use of email tracking technology to obtain data on if you open an email or if you click on any links in an email. This data will be used only in automated ways to help improve future marketing messaging and/or to prioritize follow ups based on perceived communications relevance. Without your consent, we will not make use of personal data unique to you, such as your IP address, your device and browser information, or the time and number of times you open an email or click on a link.

## Access

We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. You can email us to learn how to access and/or update the personal information you provide to InfoQ. InfoQ does not charge for this service and responds to reasonable requests in an appropriate time frame.

## Data erasure & Processing choices

You can instruct InfoQ to cease processing or erase your personal data by emailing us. Where this request does not impact the freedoms and rights of others, as defined by EU privacy regulations, we will act on your instructions in a reasonable time frame and use appropriate resources to comply with your request. The withdrawal of consent or erasure of data from an individual to cease processing will not invalidate the original legitimate and lawful basis for the processing of personal data as outlined in this notice.

## Data Portability

You may have the right to instruct InfoQ to transfer personal data relating to you to another company. Where this request does not impact the freedoms and rights of others as defined by EU privacy regulations, we will act on your instructions in a reasonable time frame and use appropriate resources to comply with your request. The transfer of your personal data will not invalidate the original legitimate and lawful basis for the processing of personal data as outlined in this notice. You can [email us](mailto:privacy@c4media.com) about this.

InfoQ is not responsible for another company accepting the data transfer in whole or in part. InfoQ will not be responsible for the data on completion of the transfer of data in whole or in part to another company regarding their obligations under EU privacy regulations.

On completion of the data transfer to another company, you can instruct InfoQ to cease processing and store the transferred data, delete the transferred data or continue processing the transferred data.

## Right to object

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data by InfoQ. You can email us to object, or you can object to an appropriate data protection authority.

Details of the UK data protection authority:  
Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Wilmslow  
SK9 5AF  
Tel: 0303 123 1113  
<https://ico.org.uk/>

Details of the Canadian data protection authority:  
Office of the Privacy Commissioner  
of Canada  
30, Victoria Street  
Gatineau, Quebec  
K1A 1H3  
Toll-free: 1-800-282-1376  
<https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/>

## Links to Third-Party sites and social media

InfoQ sites may include links to third-party sites. InfoQ does not control these third-party sites, and we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every site you visit.

## Social Networks and Third-party plug-ins

Our website may include plugins from social networks or other third parties. An example of a plugin is the Facebook “Like” button. Where legally permitted, these plugins may communicate with and send information to the party that provided the plugin, even if you do not click on the plugin. This information may include your IP address, information about your browser and device or the address of the web page you are visiting on our site. Loading, using or clicking the plugins may also place, read and transmit cookies. These cookies may contain a unique identifier the social network or third party assigns to you. The loading, functionality and your use of the plugins are governed by the privacy policy and terms of the party that provided the plugin.

## Social Network and Third-party login

Our website may allow you to log in using a social network or other third-party account. An example of a third-party login is “Log in with Facebook.” Logging into one of our sites with your social network or other third-party account may allow us to gather information that you give us permission to access from that social network or third party. The login feature may also transfer information to the social network or third party, such as your username and password, to authenticate you. The social network or third party may also automatically collect information such as your IP address, information about your browser and device, and the address of the web page you are visiting on our site. The login feature may also place and read cookies from that third party that may contain a unique identifier the social network or other third party assigns to you. The functionality of and your use of the login is governed by the privacy policy and terms of the party that provided the login functionality.

## User Generated Content

Some InfoQ and applications enable users to submit their own content for contests, blogs, videos, and other functions. Please remember that any information you submit or post as user-generated content to InfoQ sites become public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in such submissions or posts. InfoQ cannot prevent others from using such information in a manner that may violate this Privacy Policy, the law, or your personal privacy and safety. InfoQ is not responsible for the results of such postings.
